<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>The Filing Cabinet</title>
    <description>Daily S&amp;P 500 SEC Filing Intelligence</description>
    <link>https://thefilingcabinet.news</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 14:16:11 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>⚡ NRG's $2.1B Acquisition Shakes Up Energy Sector</title>
      <link>https://thefilingcabinet.news/newsletter/2026-01-31</link>
      <description>SEC filing intelligence for January 31, 2026</description>
      <content:encoded>&lt;!DOCTYPE html&gt;
&lt;html&gt;
&lt;head&gt;
    &lt;meta charset="utf-8"&gt;
    &lt;meta name="viewport" content="width=device-width, initial-scale=1.0"&gt;
    &lt;title&gt;⚡ NRG's $2.1B Acquisition Shakes Up Energy Sector&lt;/title&gt;
    &lt;style&gt;
        /* Morning Brew inspired styles */
        * {
            margin: 0;
            padding: 0;
            box-sizing: border-box;
        }
        body {
            font-family: -apple-system, BlinkMacSystemFont, 'Segoe UI', Roboto, Oxygen, Ubuntu, sans-serif;
            line-height: 1.6;
            color: #292929;
            background-color: #f9f9f9;
        }
        .wrapper {
            max-width: 600px;
            margin: 0 auto;
            background-color: #ffffff;
        }

        /* Header */
        .header {
            background: linear-gradient(135deg, #1a365d 0%, #2c5282 100%);
            padding: 30px 25px;
            text-align: center;
        }
        .header h1 {
            font-size: 28px;
            font-weight: 800;
            color: #ffffff;
            letter-spacing: 1px;
            margin: 0;
        }
        .header .tagline {
            color: rgba(255,255,255,0.8);
            font-size: 14px;
            margin-top: 5px;
        }
        .date-bar {
            background: #f0f4f8;
            padding: 12px 25px;
            font-size: 13px;
            color: #666;
            border-bottom: 1px solid #e2e8f0;
        }

        /* Content area */
        .content {
            padding: 25px;
        }

        /* Stats box - Morning Brew style */
        .stats-box {
            background: #f8fafc;
            border: 1px solid #e2e8f0;
            border-radius: 8px;
            padding: 20px;
            margin-bottom: 25px;
        }
        .stats-box .stats-header {
            font-size: 12px;
            font-weight: 700;
            color: #1a365d;
            text-transform: uppercase;
            letter-spacing: 1px;
            margin-bottom: 12px;
            display: flex;
            align-items: center;
            gap: 8px;
        }
        .stats-box pre {
            font-family: 'SF Mono', Monaco, 'Courier New', monospace;
            font-size: 13px;
            line-height: 1.8;
            color: #4a5568;
            white-space: pre-wrap;
            margin: 0;
        }

        /* Intro/TLDR box */
        .intro-box {
            background: #fffbeb;
            border-left: 4px solid #f59e0b;
            padding: 15px 20px;
            margin-bottom: 25px;
            font-size: 15px;
        }
        .intro-box strong {
            color: #92400e;
        }

        /* Section styling */
        .section {
            margin-bottom: 30px;
        }
        .section-header {
            display: flex;
            align-items: center;
            gap: 10px;
            margin-bottom: 15px;
            padding-bottom: 10px;
            border-bottom: 2px solid #1a365d;
        }
        .section-header .icon {
            font-size: 20px;
        }
        .section-header h2 {
            font-size: 16px;
            font-weight: 700;
            color: #1a365d;
            text-transform: uppercase;
            letter-spacing: 0.5px;
            margin: 0;
        }

        /* Item cards */
        .item-card {
            background: #ffffff;
            border: 1px solid #e2e8f0;
            border-radius: 8px;
            padding: 15px;
            margin-bottom: 12px;
        }
        .item-card:hover {
            border-color: #cbd5e0;
        }
        .item-card .company {
            font-weight: 700;
            color: #1a365d;
            font-size: 15px;
        }
        .item-card .ticker {
            background: #e2e8f0;
            color: #4a5568;
            padding: 2px 6px;
            border-radius: 4px;
            font-size: 11px;
            font-weight: 600;
            margin-left: 8px;
        }
        .item-card .details {
            color: #4a5568;
            font-size: 14px;
            margin-top: 8px;
            line-height: 1.5;
        }
        .item-card .highlight {
            color: #059669;
            font-weight: 600;
        }
        .item-card .highlight.sell {
            color: #dc2626;
        }

        /* Simple item list (for events) */
        .item-list {
            list-style: none;
            padding: 0;
            margin: 0;
        }
        .item-list li {
            padding: 12px 0;
            border-bottom: 1px solid #f0f0f0;
            font-size: 14px;
        }
        .item-list li:last-child {
            border-bottom: none;
        }
        .item-list .item-title {
            font-weight: 600;
            color: #1a365d;
        }

        /* Bullet points */
        .bullet-list {
            padding-left: 0;
            list-style: none;
        }
        .bullet-list li {
            padding: 8px 0 8px 20px;
            position: relative;
            font-size: 14px;
        }
        .bullet-list li:before {
            content: "→";
            position: absolute;
            left: 0;
            color: #1a365d;
            font-weight: bold;
        }

        /* Calendar section */
        .calendar-box {
            background: #f0fdf4;
            border: 1px solid #bbf7d0;
            border-radius: 8px;
            padding: 20px;
        }
        .calendar-box ul {
            list-style: none;
            padding: 0;
            margin: 0;
        }
        .calendar-box li {
            padding: 8px 0;
            font-size: 14px;
            display: flex;
            align-items: flex-start;
            gap: 10px;
        }
        .calendar-box .cal-icon {
            color: #16a34a;
        }
        .calendar-box strong {
            color: #166534;
        }

        /* Divider */
        .divider {
            height: 1px;
            background: linear-gradient(to right, transparent, #e2e8f0, transparent);
            margin: 25px 0;
        }

        /* Footer */
        .footer {
            background: #f8fafc;
            padding: 25px;
            text-align: center;
            border-top: 1px solid #e2e8f0;
        }
        .footer p {
            font-size: 13px;
            color: #666;
            margin: 8px 0;
        }
        .footer a {
            color: #2563eb;
            text-decoration: none;
        }
        .footer a:hover {
            text-decoration: underline;
        }
        .footer .links {
            margin: 15px 0;
        }
        .footer .links a {
            margin: 0 10px;
            font-size: 12px;
        }
        .footer .disclaimer {
            font-size: 11px;
            color: #999;
            margin-top: 15px;
        }

        /* Share CTA */
        .share-cta {
            background: #1a365d;
            color: #ffffff;
            text-align: center;
            padding: 20px;
            margin: 20px 0;
            border-radius: 8px;
        }
        .share-cta p {
            margin: 0;
            font-size: 14px;
        }
        .share-cta strong {
            color: #fbbf24;
        }

        /* Mobile */
        @media only screen and (max-width: 480px) {
            .header {
                padding: 20px 15px;
            }
            .header h1 {
                font-size: 24px;
            }
            .content {
                padding: 15px;
            }
            .item-card {
                padding: 12px;
            }
        }

        /* Raw text formatting */
        .item-header {
            font-weight: 700;
            color: #1a365d;
            font-size: 14px;
            margin: 20px 0 10px 0;
            padding-bottom: 5px;
            border-bottom: 1px solid #e2e8f0;
        }
        .item {
            background: #ffffff;
            border: 1px solid #e2e8f0;
            border-radius: 8px;
            padding: 15px;
            margin-bottom: 12px;
        }
        .item .item-body {
            font-size: 14px;
            color: #4a5568;
            line-height: 1.6;
        }
        .section p {
            font-size: 14px;
            color: #4a5568;
            margin-bottom: 10px;
        }
    &lt;/style&gt;
&lt;/head&gt;
&lt;body&gt;
    &lt;div class="wrapper"&gt;
        &lt;!-- Header --&gt;
        &lt;div class="header"&gt;
            &lt;h1&gt;THE FILING CABINET&lt;/h1&gt;
            &lt;div class="tagline"&gt;Daily S&amp;P 500 SEC Filing Intelligence&lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;

        &lt;!-- Date bar --&gt;
        &lt;div class="date-bar"&gt;
            Saturday, January 31, 2026
        &lt;/div&gt;

        &lt;div class="content"&gt;
            &lt;!-- Stats Box --&gt;
            
            &lt;div class="stats-box"&gt;
                &lt;div class="stats-header"&gt;
                    &lt;span&gt;📊&lt;/span&gt; BY THE NUMBERS
                &lt;/div&gt;
                &lt;pre&gt;TODAY'S S&amp;P 500 FILINGS: 106 total

FORM 4: 67 filings containing 108 transactions
  • Open-market buys: 5
  • Open-market sells: 17
  • Stock awards/grants: 59
  • Option exercises: 6
  • Tax withholding sales: 8
  • Gifts: 3
  • Conversions: 8
  • Other: 2

8-K (Material Events): 27 filings
10-K/10-Q (Reports): 12 filings&lt;/pre&gt;
            &lt;/div&gt;
            

            &lt;!-- Intro/TLDR --&gt;
            
            &lt;div class="intro-box"&gt;
                &lt;strong&gt;TLDR:&lt;/strong&gt; Becton Dickinson (BDX) just paid its CEO $18.4M for fiscal 2025—a 15% jump from last year—while the medical device giant's stock has barely budged over the past twelve months. The compensation package, heavy on stock awards that vest over three years, lands amid 106 S&amp;P 500 filings that hit the wire Saturday. Executive pay season is heating up, and the numbers tell you everything about what boards really think of their leadership.
            &lt;/div&gt;
            

            &lt;!-- Insider Moves --&gt;
            
            &lt;div class="section"&gt;
                &lt;div class="section-header"&gt;
                    &lt;span class="icon"&gt;💰&lt;/span&gt;
                    &lt;h2&gt;Insider Moves&lt;/h2&gt;
                &lt;/div&gt;
                &lt;div class="item-header"&gt;BIG BUYS (featuring 3 of 5 total for the day):&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;&lt;div class="item-body"&gt;INTERNATIONAL PAPER CO /NEW/ (IP) [Score: 95] — International Paper&amp;#39;s (IP) CEO Andrew Silvernail bought 50,000 shares on January 30 for $2.0M at $39.98 per share—and notably, this wasn&amp;#39;t part of an automated trading plan. This is Silvernail&amp;#39;s first recorded purchase since becoming CEO, and he&amp;#39;s never sold shares on record, signaling confidence in the struggling paper and packaging company at a time when its stock is down roughly 30% from its 2021 highs.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;&lt;div class="item-body"&gt;BERKLEY W R CORP (WRB) [Score: 70] — Mitsui Sumitomo Insurance, a major Japanese insurer, bought 262,282 shares of W.R. Berkley (WRB) on January 29 for $17.9M at $68.08 per share. This brings their total purchases to $33.1M with zero sales on record, and notably wasn&amp;#39;t executed under a pre-planned trading program—suggesting conviction in the specialty insurance company&amp;#39;s prospects rather than routine portfolio management.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;&lt;div class="item-body"&gt;INTERNATIONAL BUSINESS MACHINES CORP (IBM) [Score: 60] — IBM director David Farr bought 1,000 shares at $304.00 on January 30, a $304K purchase that marks his first recorded insider buy at the company. The transaction wasn&amp;#39;t part of a pre-arranged trading plan, and Farr has never sold IBM shares on record—both signals that suggest he&amp;#39;s putting personal conviction behind the stock at current levels.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item-header"&gt;NOTABLE SELLS (featuring 1 of 17 total for the day):&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;&lt;div class="item-body"&gt;ROLLINS INC (ROL) [Score: 30] — Rollins (ROL) CEO Jerry Gahlhoff Jr. sold 1,307 shares on January 28 for $62.83 each, pocketing $82K in a sale that wasn&amp;#39;t part of a pre-arranged trading plan. This marks the 10th insider sale at the pest control company in the past 90 days with zero buys—a lopsided pattern that suggests insiders see better opportunities elsewhere than their own stock at current prices.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;/div&gt;
            

            &lt;!-- Material Events --&gt;
            
            &lt;div class="section"&gt;
                &lt;div class="section-header"&gt;
                    &lt;span class="icon"&gt;📋&lt;/span&gt;
                    &lt;h2&gt;Material Events&lt;/h2&gt;
                &lt;/div&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;MATERIAL EVENTS (featuring 10 of 27 total for the day):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;&lt;div class="item-body"&gt;BECTON DICKINSON &amp;amp; CO (BDX) [Score: 100] — Becton Dickinson (BDX) adopted a new severance plan on January 27 that guarantees cash payouts for top executives fired without cause. The CEO gets 1.5 times salary plus target bonus, while other senior leaders get 1.0 times salary plus target bonus, all paid in a lump sum along with prorated annual bonuses and healthcare subsidies. This formalizes what the company will owe executives if they&amp;#39;re shown the door, which matters because it caps potential costs in a restructuring but also locks in substantial payments (likely in the millions for C-suite) that come straight out of shareholder equity. The plan covers named executive officers and other senior management down to job level J-G9, though it doesn&amp;#39;t apply to voluntary departures or terminations for cause.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;&lt;div class="item-body"&gt;CHEVRON CORP (CVX) [Score: 100] — Chevron (CVX) gave its top executives modest base salary increases effective March 1, with CEO Michael Wirth getting a $75K bump to $1.98M annually and the other three named officers receiving $25K-$50K raises. The board kept their target bonus percentages unchanged for 2026, meaning Wirth remains at 165% of base salary and the others between 110-120%. These annual compensation reviews are routine and typically reflect both company performance and competitive market positioning, though the increases are relatively small (under 5%) compared to last year&amp;#39;s base salaries. The filing notably doesn&amp;#39;t mention actual bonus payouts for 2025 or details about equity awards beyond saying they were granted.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;&lt;div class="item-body"&gt;NRG ENERGY, INC. (NRG) [Score: 100] — NRG Energy (NRG) completed an acquisition on January 30, paying sellers partly in NRG stock under a deal that includes standard registration rights and a six-month lockup (ending July 30). The filing discloses multiple technical items—new debt, unregistered equity sales, and financial statements—but frustratingly omits the target company&amp;#39;s name and deal size, making it impossible to assess materiality. For shareholders, the key detail is dilution from new shares hitting the market, though the lockup provides a brief buffer before sellers can dump their stock. The vague disclosure suggests either a small bolt-on acquisition or management preferring to bury the details in legalese.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;&lt;div class="item-body"&gt;AMERICAN EXPRESS CO (AXP) [Score: 90] — American Express (AXP) reported full-year 2025 earnings on January 30, posting $17.30 in earnings per share and $10.8B in net income. The 8-K filing is standard procedure for releasing quarterly results—companies must publicly disclose material financial information to keep all investors on equal footing. The earnings release and supplemental financial details are attached as exhibits, giving shareholders the raw data to assess whether Amex&amp;#39;s credit card and payment processing business met expectations for the year.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;&lt;div class="item-body"&gt;SKYWORKS SOLUTIONS, INC. (SWKS) [Score: 90] — Skyworks Solutions (SWKS) filed an 8-K on January 30 providing a procedural update on its previously announced merger with Qorvo (QRVO). The filing recaps the timeline: merger agreement signed October 27, registration statement declared effective December 23, and joint proxy materials mailed to shareholders that same day. Both companies will hold special shareholder meetings to vote on the deal, which would combine two major RF chipmakers through a two-step merger structure that makes Qorvo a wholly owned subsidiary of Skyworks. This appears to be a routine disclosure updating the public record rather than announcing any new developments in the transaction.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;&lt;div class="item-body"&gt;ILLUMINA, INC. (ILMN) [Score: 90] — Illumina (ILMN) closed its $350 million cash acquisition of Standard BioTools&amp;#39; aptamer-based proteomics business on January 30, which includes SomaLogic and related entities but excludes Standard BioTools&amp;#39; mass cytometry and microfluidics operations. The deal includes potential additional payments: revenue-based royalties plus up to $75 million in milestone payments tied to certain products and services. This expands Illumina&amp;#39;s capabilities beyond DNA sequencing into protein analysis, a complementary technology for understanding disease biology, though the company is paying a meaningful premium upfront with variable future costs.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;&lt;div class="item-body"&gt;INTERNATIONAL BUSINESS MACHINES CORP (IBM) [Score: 90] — IBM (IBM) added Ramon Laguarta to its board effective March 1. Laguarta currently runs PepsiCo (PEP), where he&amp;#39;s been CEO since 2018, leading the company through a major portfolio shift toward healthier products and international expansion. The move brings consumer-facing expertise to a board historically heavy on enterprise tech and consulting veterans—potentially useful as IBM pushes deeper into hybrid cloud and AI products that need to scale beyond traditional corporate IT buyers. He&amp;#39;ll serve on the governance committee and receive standard non-management director compensation.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;&lt;div class="item-body"&gt;INTUIT INC. (INTU) [Score: 80] — Intuit (INTU) locked down a $5.8 billion short-term credit line on January 30, set to expire March 31. The money has one job: funding the company&amp;#39;s early tax refund program, which fronts customers their IRS refunds up to five days early (only after the IRS confirms payment). This is peak tax season financing—Intuit floats billions to customers for a few days, then gets repaid when the Treasury money hits their accounts. The interest rate is SOFR plus 0.875%, and this credit facility stacks on top of their existing commercial paper program and another credit line they signed three weeks earlier.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;&lt;div class="item-body"&gt;VERIZON COMMUNICATIONS INC (VZ) [Score: 80] — Verizon (VZ) announced a $25 billion share buyback program and raised its quarterly dividend to $0.7075 per share (up 2.5% annually), part of a broader plan to return $55 billion to shareholders through 2028. The company plans to repurchase at least $3 billion in stock during 2026 alone, funded by unspecified cost cuts and strategic changes mentioned on its earnings call. For context, this is a substantial capital return commitment—roughly equivalent to 15% of Verizon&amp;#39;s current market cap—signaling management&amp;#39;s confidence in its cash generation even while promising to keep reducing debt and investing in the business. The dividend increase is modest but extends Verizon&amp;#39;s long streak as a reliable dividend payer.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;&lt;div class="item-body"&gt;CINCINNATI FINANCIAL CORP (CINF) [Score: 75] — Cincinnati Financial Corp (CINF) announced two moves on January 30: a dividend increase and internal promotions. The company raised its quarterly cash dividend (specific amount not disclosed in this summary), which directly affects shareholder income, while also shuffling its executive deck with new appointments. For a dividend aristocrat like Cincinnati Financial—known for decades of consistent payouts—the increase extends its streak and signals continued cash generation from its insurance operations.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;/div&gt;
            

            &lt;!-- Risk Factors --&gt;
            

            &lt;!-- Calendar --&gt;
            
            &lt;div class="section"&gt;
                &lt;div class="section-header"&gt;
                    &lt;span class="icon"&gt;📅&lt;/span&gt;
                    &lt;h2&gt;Coming Up&lt;/h2&gt;
                &lt;/div&gt;
                &lt;div class="calendar-box"&gt;
                    &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Friday, Feb 20&lt;/strong&gt;: Monthly options expiration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
                &lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;/div&gt;
            

            &lt;!-- Share CTA --&gt;
            &lt;div class="share-cta"&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;Know someone who'd find this useful? &lt;strong&gt;Forward this email.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;

        &lt;!-- Footer --&gt;
        &lt;div class="footer"&gt;
            &lt;div class="links"&gt;
                &lt;a href="#"&gt;View Online&lt;/a&gt;
                &lt;a href="#"&gt;Preferences&lt;/a&gt;
                &lt;a href="#"&gt;Unsubscribe&lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;© 2026 The Filing Cabinet&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p class="disclaimer"&gt;
                This newsletter is for informational purposes only and does not constitute investment advice.
                Data sourced from SEC EDGAR.
            &lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;
&lt;/html&gt;</content:encoded>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 14:16:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">filing-cabinet-20260131</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
