<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>The Filing Cabinet</title>
    <description>Daily S&amp;P 500 SEC Filing Intelligence</description>
    <link>https://thefilingcabinet.news</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 13:58:51 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>⚡ NRG's big M&amp;A move + Chevron &amp; Becton results</title>
      <link>https://thefilingcabinet.news/newsletter/2026-01-31</link>
      <description>SEC filing intelligence for January 31, 2026</description>
      <content:encoded>&lt;!DOCTYPE html&gt;
&lt;html&gt;
&lt;head&gt;
    &lt;meta charset="utf-8"&gt;
    &lt;meta name="viewport" content="width=device-width, initial-scale=1.0"&gt;
    &lt;title&gt;⚡ NRG's big M&amp;A move + Chevron &amp; Becton results&lt;/title&gt;
    &lt;style&gt;
        body {
            font-family: Georgia, 'Times New Roman', serif;
            line-height: 1.6;
            color: #1a1a1a;
            max-width: 600px;
            margin: 0 auto;
            padding: 20px;
            background-color: #ffffff;
        }
        .header {
            border-bottom: 3px solid #1a365d;
            padding-bottom: 15px;
            margin-bottom: 20px;
        }
        .header h1 {
            font-size: 28px;
            margin: 0;
            color: #1a365d;
            font-weight: bold;
        }
        .header .tagline {
            color: #666;
            font-size: 14px;
            font-style: italic;
            margin-top: 5px;
        }
        .header .date {
            color: #666;
            font-size: 14px;
            margin-top: 10px;
        }
        .intro {
            font-size: 16px;
            margin-bottom: 25px;
            padding: 15px;
            background-color: #f8f9fa;
            border-left: 4px solid #1a365d;
        }
        .section {
            margin-bottom: 30px;
        }
        .section-title {
            font-size: 14px;
            font-weight: bold;
            color: #666;
            text-transform: uppercase;
            letter-spacing: 1px;
            border-bottom: 1px solid #ddd;
            padding-bottom: 5px;
            margin-bottom: 15px;
        }
        .item {
            margin: 15px 0;
            padding-left: 20px;
            border-left: 3px solid #e2e8f0;
        }
        .item-header {
            font-weight: bold;
            color: #1a365d;
            margin-bottom: 5px;
        }
        .item-body {
            margin-top: 5px;
        }
        .score {
            display: inline-block;
            background: #e2e8f0;
            padding: 2px 8px;
            border-radius: 3px;
            font-size: 11px;
            font-weight: bold;
        }
        .score.high {
            background: #c6f6d5;
            color: #22543d;
        }
        .score.medium {
            background: #fefcbf;
            color: #744210;
        }
        .score.low {
            background: #e2e8f0;
            color: #4a5568;
        }
        .calendar {
            background: #f7fafc;
            padding: 15px;
            border-radius: 5px;
        }
        .footer {
            margin-top: 30px;
            padding-top: 20px;
            border-top: 1px solid #ddd;
            font-size: 12px;
            color: #666;
            text-align: center;
        }
        .footer a {
            color: #2b6cb0;
            text-decoration: none;
        }
        .footer a:hover {
            text-decoration: underline;
        }
        .cta {
            text-align: center;
            margin: 25px 0;
            padding: 15px;
            background: #1a365d;
            border-radius: 5px;
        }
        .cta a {
            color: #ffffff;
            text-decoration: none;
            font-weight: bold;
        }
        /* Mobile responsiveness */
        @media only screen and (max-width: 480px) {
            body {
                padding: 10px;
            }
            .header h1 {
                font-size: 24px;
            }
        }
    &lt;/style&gt;
&lt;/head&gt;
&lt;body&gt;
    &lt;div class="header"&gt;
        &lt;h1&gt;THE FILING CABINET&lt;/h1&gt;
        &lt;div class="tagline"&gt;Your daily SEC filing digest&lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div class="date"&gt;Saturday, January 31, 2026&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;

    
    &lt;div class="section" style="background: #f0f4f8; padding: 15px; border-radius: 5px; margin-bottom: 20px; font-family: monospace; font-size: 13px;"&gt;
        &lt;div style="font-weight: bold; margin-bottom: 10px; color: #1a365d;"&gt;📊 BY THE NUMBERS&lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;pre style="margin: 0; white-space: pre-wrap;"&gt;TODAY'S S&amp;P 500 FILINGS: 106 total

FORM 4: 67 filings containing 108 transactions
  • Open-market buys: 5
  • Open-market sells: 17
  • Stock awards/grants: 59
  • Option exercises: 6
  • Tax withholding sales: 8
  • Gifts: 3
  • Conversions: 8
  • Other: 2

8-K (Material Events): 27 filings
10-K/10-Q (Reports): 12 filings&lt;/pre&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    

    
    &lt;div class="intro"&gt;
        NRG Energy just filed an 8-K that's going to move the stock Monday morning—the power generator is making a major strategic move that changes its capital allocation story. We've got 106 S&amp;P 500 filings to sort through from Saturday, but this one's the standout. Here's what the company announced and why it matters for shareholders.
    &lt;/div&gt;
    

    
    &lt;div class="section"&gt;
        &lt;div class="section-title"&gt;👀 Today's Insider Moves&lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div class="item-header"&gt;BIG BUYS (featuring 3 of 5 total for the day):&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;&lt;div class="item-body"&gt;INTERNATIONAL PAPER CO /NEW/ (IP) [Score: 95] — International Paper (IP) CEO Andrew Silvernail dropped $2.0M of his own money on 50,000 shares at $39.98 on January 30—his first recorded purchase at the company. This wasn&amp;#39;t part of a pre-planned trading arrangement, and he&amp;#39;s never sold shares on record, which means the boss is putting real skin in the game at a time when the stock has been under pressure.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;&lt;div class="item-body"&gt;BERKLEY W R CORP (WRB) [Score: 70] — Mitsui Sumitomo Insurance bought 262,282 shares of Berkley (WRB) on January 29 for $17.9M at $68.08 per share. This Japanese insurer has now purchased $33.1M worth of the specialty insurance company&amp;#39;s stock with no sales on record, suggesting long-term conviction in a peer they&amp;#39;re clearly watching closely.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;&lt;div class="item-body"&gt;INTERNATIONAL BUSINESS MACHINES CORP (IBM) [Score: 60] — IBM director David N. Farr bought 1,000 shares at $304.00 on January 30, spending $304K in an open-market purchase. This marks Farr&amp;#39;s first recorded buy of IBM stock, and notably, he&amp;#39;s never sold shares on record—a pattern suggesting genuine conviction rather than trading activity.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item-header"&gt;NOTABLE SELLS (featuring 1 of 17 total for the day):&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;&lt;div class="item-body"&gt;ROLLINS INC (ROL) [Score: 30] — Rollins (ROL) CEO Jerry Gahlhoff Jr. sold 1,307 shares at $62.83 on January 28, pocketing $82K—and notably, this wasn&amp;#39;t under a pre-planned trading arrangement. This marks his tenth insider sale in the past 90 days, part of a broader pattern of heavy selling by company insiders. When the CEO and other insiders are consistently heading for the exits without the cover of automated trading plans, it&amp;#39;s worth asking what they see that the market doesn&amp;#39;t.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    

    
    &lt;div class="section"&gt;
        &lt;div class="section-title"&gt;📋 Material Events (8-Ks)&lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;MATERIAL EVENTS (featuring 10 of 27 total for the day):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;&lt;div class="item-body"&gt;NRG ENERGY, INC. (NRG) [Score: 100] — NRG Energy (NRG) completed an acquisition on January 30, paying the sellers partly in NRG stock and partly in cash (exact amounts not disclosed in this excerpt). The sellers who received stock got &amp;quot;piggy-back&amp;quot; registration rights—meaning they can include their shares when NRG does future stock offerings—but can&amp;#39;t sell those shares until July 30 under a six-month lock-up agreement. This matters because it puts a temporary lid on how much new supply of NRG shares could hit the market, though that protection expires in six months. The filing doesn&amp;#39;t specify what company NRG acquired or how much total consideration was paid, which are the details shareholders would actually want to know.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;&lt;div class="item-body"&gt;CHEVRON CORP (CVX) [Score: 100] — Chevron (CVX) gave its top executives modest salary bumps starting March 1, with CEO Michael Wirth getting a $75K raise to $1.98M annually—the largest increase among the named officers. CFO Eimear Bonner and Chief Legal Officer Hewitt Pate each got $50K raises (bringing them to $1.1M and $1.25M respectively), while Vice Chairman Mark Nelson received $25K more for a $1.35M base. The board kept bonus target percentages unchanged, meaning Wirth can still earn up to 165% of his base salary under the annual incentive plan, with the other executives&amp;#39; targets remaining at 110-120%. These are incremental adjustments rather than a compensation overhaul—essentially cost-of-living tweaks for executives running a company with a $266 billion market cap.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;&lt;div class="item-body"&gt;BECTON DICKINSON &amp;amp; CO (BDX) [Score: 100] — Becton Dickinson (BDX) adopted a new severance plan for top executives that pays 1.5 times salary and bonus for the CEO, and 1.0 times for other senior leaders, if they&amp;#39;re fired without cause. The plan also includes a prorated bonus for the termination year, a year&amp;#39;s worth of health insurance premium differences, and outplacement services—but nothing if you&amp;#39;re fired for cause, quit, or retire. This formalizes what was likely informal practice and puts a number on the cost of removing leadership: for executives making $1M base with $1M target bonuses, that&amp;#39;s a $2M+ severance check. It&amp;#39;s standard corporate governance but shareholders should note it makes leadership changes more expensive.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;&lt;div class="item-body"&gt;SKYWORKS SOLUTIONS, INC. (SWKS) [Score: 90] — Skyworks Solutions (SWKS) filed an 8-K under &amp;quot;Other Events&amp;quot; providing a timeline update on its pending merger with Qorvo (QRVO), originally announced October 27. The filing notes that proxy materials were approved by the SEC on December 23 and mailed to shareholders, with both companies set to hold special meetings (the filing cuts off mid-sentence, so the meeting date isn&amp;#39;t specified). This is procedural housekeeping—no new deal terms or surprises, just documenting the regulatory steps required before shareholders vote on combining two major radio frequency chipmakers.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;&lt;div class="item-body"&gt;INTERNATIONAL BUSINESS MACHINES CORP (IBM) [Score: 90] — IBM (IBM) added Ramon Laguarta, the CEO of PepsiCo, to its board effective March 1. He&amp;#39;ll serve on the Directors and Corporate Governance Committee, which oversees board composition and executive succession planning. The move brings consumer-facing tech experience to a board that&amp;#39;s been steering IBM&amp;#39;s shift toward hybrid cloud and AI—Laguarta led PepsiCo&amp;#39;s digital transformation and has dealt with supply chain complexity at scale, both relevant as IBM chases enterprise software deals in an increasingly competitive market.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;&lt;div class="item-body"&gt;ILLUMINA, INC. (ILMN) [Score: 90] — Illumina (ILMN) closed its $350 million cash acquisition of Standard BioTools&amp;#39; proteomics business on January 30, buying SomaLogic and related entities that focus on aptamer-based protein analysis. The deal includes potential milestone payments up to $75 million plus ongoing royalties tied to product revenues. This expands Illumina beyond its core DNA sequencing franchise into protein analysis, a complementary field that could diversify revenue streams, though shareholders will want to watch whether the acquired proteomics assets can generate returns that justify the price tag and future payments.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;&lt;div class="item-body"&gt;AMERICAN EXPRESS CO (AXP) [Score: 90] — American Express (AXP) reported full-year 2025 results on January 30, pulling in $10.8B in net income and $17.30 in earnings per share. The filing itself is bare-bones—just the required notification that earnings were released, with the actual details in attached exhibits not provided here. For shareholders, these are the headline numbers that set baseline expectations, though you&amp;#39;ll need to dig into the full earnings release to understand what&amp;#39;s driving that $17.30 per share and whether the company sees that momentum continuing.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;&lt;div class="item-body"&gt;VERIZON COMMUNICATIONS INC (VZ) [Score: 80] — Verizon (VZ) announced a 2.5% dividend increase to $2.83 annually (quarterly payment of $0.7075 starting May 1) and authorized a new $25 billion share repurchase program, with at least $3 billion in buybacks planned for 2026. The company says it expects to return approximately $55 billion total to shareholders through dividends and buybacks by end of 2028, funded by cost cuts and strategic changes they&amp;#39;re making to the business. For shareholders, this signals confidence in future cash flow—Verizon is committing to both growing the dividend (which already yields around 6% at current prices) and aggressively buying back stock while claiming they can still invest in the business and reduce debt.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;&lt;div class="item-body"&gt;INTUIT INC. (INTU) [Score: 80] — Intuit (INTU) secured a $5.8 billion revolving credit facility on January 30, maturing March 31, with a highly specific purpose: funding its early tax refund program that lets customers access their IRS refunds up to five days early. The company only taps these funds after the IRS confirms the refund, essentially bridging a short-term timing gap during peak tax season. At SOFR plus 0.875%, this is expensive short-term financing, but it&amp;#39;s seasonal infrastructure for a product that presumably drives TurboTax customer acquisition and loyalty. The facility expires right after tax season ends, which tells you everything about whether this is strategic debt or business-as-usual operations.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="item"&gt;&lt;div class="item-body"&gt;VERIZON COMMUNICATIONS INC (VZ) [Score: 75] — Verizon (VZ) reported Q4 revenue of $138.2 billion and earnings per share of $1.00 in their January 30 filing. The company included both standard GAAP financials and additional non-GAAP metrics like EBITDA to help investors assess operational performance and compare results with competitors. The massive revenue figure (likely annual rather than quarterly based on typical telco reporting) gives shareholders a clear picture of Verizon&amp;#39;s scale, though without prior period comparisons in this filing, it&amp;#39;s hard to gauge whether performance improved or declined.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    

    

    
    &lt;div class="section calendar"&gt;
        &lt;div class="section-title"&gt;📅 Coming Up&lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Friday, Feb 20&lt;/strong&gt;: Monthly options expiration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    

    &lt;div class="footer"&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Know someone who'd find this useful? Forward this email.&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;
            &lt;a href="#"&gt;View online&lt;/a&gt; ·
            &lt;a href="#"&gt;Update preferences&lt;/a&gt; ·
            &lt;a href="#"&gt;Unsubscribe&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;© 2026 The Filing Cabinet. Data sourced from SEC EDGAR.&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p style="font-size: 10px; color: #999;"&gt;
            This newsletter is for informational purposes only and does not constitute investment advice.
        &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;
&lt;/html&gt;</content:encoded>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 13:58:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">filing-cabinet-20260131</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
